Finding Aid for Mental Health Research Institute (University of Michigan) publications, 1957-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mental Health Research Institute (University of Michigan) Publications 1957-1999
University of Michigan. Mental Health Research Institute.
9741 Bimu C6 2
Includes annual reports, calendars, directories, histories, and newsletters such as Speaking of... MHRI and the MHRI Newsletter. Also includes reports such as the Markey Grant Progress Report and a reprint of the speeches delivered at the dedication of the Mental Health Research Institute.
1.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor # 3625 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Please consult the history found in the finding aid for Mental Health Research Institute (University of Michigan) records.
The Publications of the Mental Health Research Institute (1 linear foot) consist of annual reports, calendars, directories, histories, and newsletters such as Speaking of... MHRI and the MHRI Newsletter. They also include reports such as the Markey Grant Progress Report and a reprint of the speeches delivered at the dedication of the Mental Health Research Institute. The Publications are divided into two subseries: Unit Publications and Topical Publications.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Mental Health Research Institute.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; Markey grant progress report.; Construction of hypothesis model for concept identification.; MHRI newsletter.; Speaking of... MHRI.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Calendars.; Directories.; Histories.; Newsletters.; Reports.; Speeches.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications subseries includes a complete run of annual reports produced by the Mental Health Research Institute. During the period 1979-1982 no annual reports were created. This subseries also contains calendars of daily activities, directories which include both academic and support staff, and flyers which describe the Mental Health Research Institute Seminar. A photographic history entitled "The Original Living System and How It Grew: The Mental Health Research Institute, 1955-1967" is also included in this subseries though it is shelved with other large university publications in Outsize FImu C6. There are several newsletters including Internode which was published from 1965 through 1966. Speaking of...MHRI was published from 1975-1976. During 1976 the title of the publication was changed to MHRI Newsletter. The numbering of this newsletter continued from the old title. Reports include Communication 241 Construction of Hypotheses Model for Concept Identification and Communication 243 Generative Computer Assisted Instruction. Under reports there are several annual reports describing the various activities funded by the Markey Grant.
  - Annual Reports
    - 1957-1978, 9 folders (Box 1)
    - 1983-1997, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Biennial Reports
    - 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Calendars
    - What's On In Neuroscience at U-M, 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Directories
    - Alumni Directory, 1995 (Box 1)
    - List of Temporary and Non-Institute Paid Staff at MHRI, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    - MHRI Annex Lists, 1966 (Box 1)
    - MHRI Directory, 1979 (Box 1)
    - MHRI Staff Directory, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - MHRI Telephone List of Administrative Offices, Services and Secretaries, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
    - Non-Academic Staff, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
    - Scientific Coordination Area Membership, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
    - Secretaries and Supervisors, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Staff Listing, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - Flyers
    - Mental Health Research Institute Seminar, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Histories
    - The Original Living System and How It Grew: The Mental Health Research Institute, 1955-1967, [1967] (Box 1)
      ([Removed to outsize material--FImu C6])
  - Invitations
    - Brainstorms: Insights Into Neural Plasticity, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - The Back Page, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Internode, 1965-1966 vol. 1, no. 1-7 (Box 1)
    - MHRI Newsletter, 1976-1979 vol. 2, no. 3-vol. 5, no. 2 (Box 1)
      [supersedes Speaking of ...MHRI]
    - Speaking of ...MHRI, 1975-1976 vol. 1-vol. 2, no. 2 (Box 1)
      [precedes MHRI Newsletter]
  - Programs
    - Brainstorms: Insights into Neural Plasticity, a Symposium in Honor of Dr. Bernard W. Agranoff, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Inauguration of Raymond W. Waggoner Conference Room, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - National Political Units in the 20th Century: A Standardized List, Communication 219, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Construction of Hypotheses Model for Concept Identification, Communication 241, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Generative Computer Assisted Instruction, Communication 243, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Markey Grant Progress Report for Period..., 1989-1993, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Reprints (Box 2)
    - 1968 Parts 1 and 3 (of 4) (Box 2)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications subseries includes programs and speeches documenting the dedication ceremonies of the Mental Health Research Institute building. Programs and flyers describe the fortieth anniversary symposium of the institute.
  - Dedication Ceremonies of the Mental Health Research Institute, 1960 includes invitation and brief speeches (Box 2)
  - Symposium to Celebrate the 40th Anniversary of the Mental Health Research Institute, 1995 includes programs and flyers (Box 2)